Arta Khosravi She/Her

(+98) 902 200 8277

O artakh10

✓ artakh1o@gmail.com

With a Master of Science degree in Gravity and Cosmology, my research interests encompass Accretion Disks, Active Galactic Nuclei, Dark Energy and Dark Matter, Black Hole Cosmology, Epoch of Re-ionization, and Negative mass cosmology. As a Research Assistant with more than two years of experience, I am dedicated to advancing our understanding of the universe through cutting-edge research and using computational analysis methods.

Education

m Shahid Beheshti University

2021 - 2023

M.Sc of Gravity and Cosmology

Tehran, Iran

- Thesis Title: Negative Mass Cosmology with SNIa and BAO Data.
- · Supervisors: Prof. Marzieh Farhang, Prof. Hossein Shojaei
- · Thesis Grade: Outstanding
- Overall GPA: 14.89/20 (WES format: 3.2/4.0)

m Shahid Beheshti University

2016 - 2021

B.Sc of Physics

Tehran, Iran

- Overall GPA: 15.49/20 (GPA of last year: 17.92/20) (WES format: 3.03/4.0; WES format of last year: 4.0/4.0) Final Projects:
- Thesis title: Exoplanets and Habitable Zones
- · Supervisor: Prof. Nima Khosravi
- Importance of Quasars for Dark Energy properties: during the Cosmology Undergraduate course

Research Experience

Dec. 2023 - Present

Research Assistant

Tehran, Iran

> Cosmological Models by considering large-scale structures via the Friends of Friends Algorithm. (Paper is under preparation.) Using Python's Data Analysis to efficiently group AGNs with the Friends of Friends Algorithm, applying flux and volume constraints from QUOTAS Dataset. Code is available upon request.

PDAT – Physics Data and Astronomy Technology Laboratory

April 2023 - Present Tehran, Iran

Research Assistant

Research Assistant

Research Assistant Intern

> Working on "On the Accretion Efficiency of High Redshift Quasars based on the QUOTAS & QuasarNet Data set". (Paper is under preparation.)

Using Data Analysis and Machine Learning to Investigate the Relations between Black Hole Accretion Rate and Super Massive Black Hole Mass, Bolometric Luminosity, Radiation Rate, λL_{λ} or specifically L_{5100} , Eddington Ratio (λ_{edd}) and Redshift Using QUOTAS Data and to find the best fit with logical parameters. Code and draft are available upon request.

PDAT – Physics Data and Astronomy Technology Laboratory

Jan. 2023 – April 2023

Tehran, Iran

> Worked on rotating Black Hole's Spin Effect on Black Hole Accretion Rate.

Using Data Analysis via Python to Investigate whether a rotating BH's Spin (a) can affect BH's Accretion efficiency or not.

m PDAT – Physics Data and Astronomy Technology Laboratory

Sep. 2022 - Jan. 2023

Tehran, Iran

> Worked on Thermal Evolution from 21cm emission.

Using Data Analysis via Python to solve the Thermal evolution equation from 21cm heating, Ly α heating, and X-ray heating; and Investigating the relation between T_k and T_{spin} with Redshift using 21CMSOLVER code.

m Shahid Beheshti University

Research Assistant

Jun. 2022 – Oct. 2023 Tehran, Iran

- > M.Sc. Thesis Title: Negative Mass Cosmology with SNIa and BAO Data. The Github code is available here; and is in preparation to be published.
- > Abstract: The Thesis presents the concept of negative mass in the cosmological model. We explore the potential impact of negative mass on the acceleration of the universe's expansion and its role as a component of the cosmos. The study aims to determine if the cosmological constant and cold dark matter can assume negative values within this model. A novel model is proposed to explain the observed positive acceleration of the cosmos in terms of the Hubble parameter while discounting certain characteristics. The model is tested using type Ia supernovae and baryon acoustic oscillations data, revealing two scenarios for obtaining the best values of cosmic parameters. It is important to note that this project does not investigate the negative mass cluster.
- > Supervisors: Prof. Marzieh Farhang, Prof. Hossein Shojaei
- > Future Aspects Include: Investigating the effects of Negative mass and comparing the data by adding another set of parameters Using MCMC.

m Shahid Beheshti University

Nov. 2019 – Jun. 2020 Tehran, Iran

Research Assistant

» B.Sc. Thesis Title: Exoplanets and Habitable Zones.

- > Supervisor: Prof. Nima Khosravi
- > Abstract: Exoplanets are planets that orbit stars other than the sun, offering valuable information about planetary formation, evolution, and the possibility of extraterrestrial life. Despite challenges in detection and characterization, the study of exoplanets is crucial for understanding their significance to Earth and exploring potential habitable zones.

Publications

A. Khosravi, A. Karamzadeh, S.S. Tabasi, J.T. Firoozjaei, "On the Accretion Efficiency of High Redshift Quasars based on the QUOTAS & QuasarNet Data set"

> Under preparation.

A. Khosravi, S.S. Tabasi, J.T. Firoozjaei, "Cosmological Models by considering large-scale structures via the Friends of Friends Algorithm."

> Under preparation.

Teacher Assistant

Teaching Assistant Experience

m Shahid Beheshti University

Feb. 2023 – Jun. 2023

Tehran, Iran

- > Course: Cosmology (I) for Graduate Students
- > Reference: Cosmology by Daniel Baumann
- > Lecturer: Prof. Hossein Shojaei
- > Highlights: Responsible for holding exercise classes, Designing computational exercises using Python and Mathematica, preparing students, recitations, and grading homework.

Workshops, Seminars, and Meetings

Cosmology: From Theory to Observation

Institude for Research in Fundamental Sciences (IPM)

Cosmology and Astrophysics with New Data

K. N. Toosi University of Technology

Machine Learning and Physics

SciSchool Institude

Statistical Analysis of Cosmic Fields

Shahid Beheshti University

Introduction to Various Topics in Quantum Physics

Inter Disciplinary Schools

Tehran, Iran Jul. 2022

Aug. 2023

Tehran, Iran

June. 2022

Tehran, Iran

eman, man

Oct. 2021

Tehran, Iran

Oct. 2020

Tehran, Iran

Introduction to Cosmology

Inter Disciplinary Schools

Neuroscience: From Conciseness to Memory

Sharif University of Technology

Oct. 2020 Tehran, Iran Sep. 2019 Tehran, Iran

Q Research Interests

- Data Driven Cosmology
- Computational Cosmology and Astrophysics
- Accretion disks (Accretion efficiency)
- Active Galactic Nuclei (Quasars)
- PBH and SMBH cosmology
- Dark matter and Dark Energy
- 21cm Cosmology
- Large Scale Structure
- Epoch of Re-ionization
- Intergalactic Mediums
- Negative Mass Cosmology
- Interactive Dark Matter and Dark Energy (IDM)

⇔ Skills

Programming Languages Python, HTML/CSS, C++

Development Tools, Algorithms and Technologies Pandas, Seaborn, Matplotlib, SciPy, SymPy, NumPy, Scikit-Learn, TensorFlow, Git, Jupyter Notebook, WordPress, Friends of Friends (FOF) Algorithm, MCMC Algorithm, etc.

Softwares Wolfram Mathematica (xAct, etc.), Astrometrica, Microsoft Office, Adobe (Photoshop, After Effects, InDesign)

Industry Knowledge Machine Learning, Data Analysis, Statistical Data Analysis, Numerical Analysis

Markup Languages LaTeX

Languages English (Full professional proficiency), Farsi (Native), Dutch (Basic), French (Basic) **Familiar with** Linux, Julia, Jekyll, 21cm Cosmology, BH cosmology, Negative mass Cosmology, IDM

P Honors and Awards

Ranked within the top %10 in Gravity and Cosmology among my M.Sc. graduating class. Shahid Beheshti University	Sept. 2023 Tehran, Iran
Ranked within the top %15 in Physics among my B.Sc. graduating class. Shahid Beheshti University	Dec. 2020 Tehran, Iran
Ranked within the top %2 In the Iranian University Entrance Exam for Master Degree. For Shahid Beheshti University	2021 Tehran, Iran
Ranked within the top %3 In the Iranian University Entrance Exam for Bachelor Degree. For Shahid Beheshti University	2016 Tehran, Iran
Got Through the first level of Astronomy Student Olympiad. Manzoumeh Kherad Institute	2015 Tehran, Iran
Got Through the first level of Physics Student Olympiad. Manzoumeh Kherad Institute	2015 Tehran, Iran
Ranked within the Top three projects in Physics and Astrophysics Society two years in a row. Manzoumeh Kherad Institute	2014–2015 Tehran, Iran

Relevant Courses

Supervised Machine Learning: Regression and Classification

Coursera

by Andrew NG

Data Analysis Using Python

by Mahdieh Tavakoli

Pazhvak Danesh

Introduction to General Relativity In Mathematica Using xAct

by Sajad Aghapoor

Graduate Cosmology (II) Shahid Beheshti University

by Prof. Nima Khosravi Grade: 4.0/4.0

SciSchool Institute

Advanced Astrophysics (I)

Shahid Beheshti University

by Prof. Sadollah Nasiri Gheydari Grade: 4.0/4.0

Under-Graduate Cosmology Shahid Beheshti University

by Prof. Nima Khosravi Grade: 4.0/4.0

Under-Graduate Astronomy & **Astrophysics**Shahid Beheshti University

by Prof. Nima Khosravi Grade: 4.0/4.0

Earth in Space Shahid Beheshti University

by Prof. Alireza Salehipoor Grade: 4.0/4.0

References

Prof. Marzieh Farhang | Associate Professor at Physics Department of Shahid Beheshti University

M.Sc. Supervisor

■ Email: M_farhang [at] sbu.ac.ir

Prof. Javad Taghizadeh Firouzjaee | Associate Professor at Physics Department of Khajeh Nasir Toosi University of Technology

Supervisor at Physics Data and Astronomy Technology Laboratory

■ Email: firouzjaee [at] kntu.ac.ir

Prof. Hossein Shojaei | Assistant Professor at Physics Department of Shahid Beheshti University

M.Sc. Supervisor